朱丽叶·比诺什
妮可·加西亚
弗朗索瓦·西维尔
导 演
萨菲·奈布
你觉得我是谁
米约夫人
Shr. Nillud?
下次可以晚一点么  我早上吃了镇定药不是很舒服
This can be done later next time? I 'm not in form in the morning because of the Valium.
这个慢点我们再讨论
We will discuss this later.
齐曼医生明白的  我们总是约在午饭后
Dr. Zimman understand it. We always did it after lunch.
我明白
I get it.
齐曼医生真是倒霉  现在中风了
What misfortune Dr. Zimman have suffered a stroke soon now.
我们必须重新开始么  重复我说过的
We have to start all over again? It's like I'm repeating myself.
不用  我们换一种方式聊聊吧
No, we will not repeat. We will discuss things from a different point of view.
这种改变会很有用的
This change can be very helpful.
看起来你想问问我的职务  是么
You seem to want to ask questions about my position. Or not?
关于我是怎么工作的
About my work.
你名字叫凯瑟琳·鲍曼  你是一个医生
Her name is Catherine Bormans, you're a doctor,
你专攻精神病学  你是一名心理医生
It specializes in psychiatry and is a psychotherapist.
你在不同的医院工作了20年
You have 20 years of experience in different hospitals
短期内你可以在这个诊所代替齐曼医生
and may in the short term to replace Dr. Zimman this clinic.
这些我都可以在谷歌上查到
I could find it on Google.
我有想象过你的与众不同
I imagined you differently.
更加年轻
Younger.
你意识到了最重要的一点
Do you know the most important things.
我应该从哪开始
Where should I start?
你想从哪开始呢
Wherever you start?
鲁多
Ludo.
最好说说鲁多
It is better to talk about Ludo.
一个新项目  嗯
A new project? Yes.
海滩旁边的一个酒吧
A bar across the sea.
这照片不错
Beautiful pictures.
亚历克斯拍的  亚历克斯
It was Alex who did. Alex?
一个摄影师  现在和我在一起
你不是不喜欢有人待在你那里么
He lives with me. A photographer. You did not want people there, is not it?
不是一回事  我了解他  我们一直在一起玩
It's different, I knew him. We play together.
他刚刚被甩了
Just be abandoned.
那个很不错  看起来很美  是么
It's beautiful, you have a beautiful appearance. You think?
我得走了  我预约了出租车  必须得现在走吗
I have to go, I called a Uber. You have to leave now?
酒吧老板明天想见我  我们应该要一块过周末的
The owner of the bar wants to see me tomorrow. We would spend the weekend together.
生气了
You are in a bad mood now?
你这个年纪也会这样么
You're not too old for this?
你没有生气
Do not play boring.
我不理解你为什么要这么做
I do not understand why you do it.
什么  为什么要给我打电话
Is that ... Why do you call me
要是你不喜欢和我在一起的话
if you have no desire to be with me?
我很享受跟你在一起的时光
I love to enjoy my time with you.
你有想过向你的儿子们介绍我吗
You sometimes see me as your children?
我可以当他们的兄弟
I could be their brother.
如果你不想再见到我  我不是那个意思
If you prefer not to see me again ... I do not mean it.
你说的
You tell me.
我可以在那下车吗
You can leave me out front, please?
电话联系
We talk, huh?
拉克洛《风险关系》骇人听闻地出版后  他怎么样了
What happened to Laclos after the scandal of risk relationships?
因为这个文人是个行动主义者
This writer is primarily a man of action.
一个战士  一个工程师  一个有信仰的人
A soldier, an engineer , and a man of conviction.
法国大革命对他而言是一个叙写历史的机会
The French Revolution is the time for him to write the story.
作为奥尔良公爵的追随者  他突然在
Even being a disciple of the Duke of Orleans, he is suddenly caught in ...
在
He was arrested in ...
他突然在
在1793年
In 1793?
在1793年被捕  谢谢
In 1793. Thank you.
他被关在军队监狱  后来去了皮克毕
He goes first to the arrest of the Armed Forces and then to the cemetery of Picpus.
谁能想象最后自己被关了起来
Who do you think who will be a year later locked between the same walls?
你好
Hello.
你好  请问你是
Hello, I'm talking to?
我是鲁多的朋友  你是谁
Ludo's friend. Who are you?
你能  能让他听电话吗
You can ... you can put it on the line for a minute?
不行  他在开牡蛎  我是克莱尔
No, he's opening oysters. I'm Claire.
克莱尔  克莱尔是谁  鲁多
Claire, Claire, quem? Ludo?
你认识一个叫克莱尔的么  不  我不认识
Do you know a Claire? No, I do not know Claire.
什么  我想你可能搞错了
Excuse me. I think you're wrong.
你能让他听电话吗
You can put it on the line for a minute?
我是亚历克斯  鲁多的助手  他会尽快回你电话的
I'm Alex, Ludo assistant. He will call you as soon as possible.
好么  好的  但我现在能跟他说句话么
Okay, okay, but I can talk to Ludo?
他现在不在
He is not here.
我听到他的声音了  他刚走
I just heard it. He just left home.
听着  别开玩笑
Listen, no fun.
鲁多没有接受你的邀请
Ludo has not accepted your invitation.
你用社交媒体么  医生
You are on social media, Dr. Bormans?
对于像我这样的人来说
For people like me, they are both,
就像溺水的木筏
a shipwreck and a ferry.
在数字世界里飘荡
You float in the digital world.
有时你是猎人  有时
Sometimes you're the spider, sometimes it can
你是猎物
fly.
注册
Register.
克拉拉
Clara ...
克拉拉·安东尼斯
Clara Antunes.
出生日期
Date of birth.
24  25岁
24, 25 ...
我对亚历克斯没什么印象
我不认识他  他也没跟我说过话
I did not have Alex in mind. I did not know, he did not tell me anything.
我试图在Facebook上接触他  来接近鲁多
I approached him on Facebook to approach me Ludo.
发送好友申请
sent friend request
我不用等太久
I did not have to wait long.
点赞
How...
谢谢你给我的照片点赞
Glad you like my photos.
它们都棒极了
They are magnificent.
喔  谢谢
Wow!! Thanks.
你很有天赋  晚安
You have a lot of talent. Have a good night.
等等   你最喜欢哪一张呢
Hang on! Which do you prefer?
没法选啊  我都很喜欢
All. I can not choose.
你是做什么工作的
what kind of job do you do?
我是时尚行业的
I'm in the fashion industry.
时尚模特
Model?
别激动
Do not get carried away.
我组织时尚活动
I organize fashion events.
我当实习生  他们给的工资很高
As a trainee. They pay a lot of money.
没懂
I do not know that expression.
我老板是个讨厌鬼
My boss is a big miser.
小气鬼
petty man.
我的老板一般般
My boss is a loser ...
但简历看来很不错
but looks good on my resume.
我有时间  我还年轻
I have time, I'm still young.
怎么样
How was it?
还行
We left.
有什么特别的吗
You did something special?
有啊
We play.
哦  还不错  嗯
Well, it was not pleasant? Yes.
她也在那么
She was there?
跟我没什么关系是吗
It does not bother me anymore.
在的  是么
Sure. Really.
你为什么要问这个  就像连体双胞胎
Why are you asking? It's like Siamese twins.
他们太傻了
They are so stupid.
谁赢了
Who won?
她第一  爸爸第二  我记得
The first time she and Dad after that. I believe.
不是你
Not you?
他是最后一名  失败者  闭嘴
He was the last, the loser. Shut up.
在这我们可以说法语  没关系的
We can speak French here is good.
马克斯  吃饭别玩手机
Max, not on the table.
“孩子 不要嫉妒  吾们疼痛的年纪
那儿  心头小鹿  沦为奴隶——揭竿而起（雨果《写给一位年轻的姑娘》）
"Child, do not envy for our age, in which the heart is rebellious slave
那儿  拈花一笑  常常比你们的泪滴还忧郁
In the saddest laughter are tears
噢  莫要急急忙忙  成熟你们的思想
尽情享受晨光  拥吻春姑娘
Do not rush your thoughts Enjoy the morning, spring
你们的  一分一秒  落英缤纷
花儿般缠绕  莫搅快了  时光木马的漩涡”
His days are as tangled flowers Not colhas prematurely leaves "
没什么振奋人心的  抱歉这是给老人看的
Not really inspiring. Sorry, it's for the elderly.
主题就是这样
Well, you get the theme, it's something.
那我现在该做什么
And what should I do now?
你怎么通过中学毕业会考的
I do not have to pass a final exam this year.
还在开会
Always meeting ...
他是怎样的风格
What figures of speech he uses?
他的押韵怎么样
What is the standard of rhyme?
很好
You do not know?
我想帮你  但你也得动动脑筋
I want to help but think for yourself too.
随便了
Ok, ok, too.
别生气
Do not be angry.
这是交叉押韵  ABAB
It is a cross rhyme, ABAB.
一共有三种风格
There are three figures of style.
你听说过隐喻吗
Have you heard of metaphors?
那个小绿灯
This small green light ...
说明对方也和你一样在线
indicating that the other is also online, just like you ...
在他那头也是一样
on their screen.
当你看到绿光时是什么感觉
How did you feel when you saw this green light?
安心
Comfort.
一口凡托林  我就可以更好呼吸
A Ventolin capsule (medicine) and I could breathe better.
我
I am ...
很丑
very ugly ...
而且很老
and very old.
那种兴奋感
The excitement ...
也很风趣
It is also funny.
可能他正关注着你
Maybe he's watching what you do,
你评论的图片  你正在听的音乐
the photos you said, the music you hear ...
你根本不知道对方了解你多少  真的很疯狂
Very mad that they know everything about you.
我在Insta上找不到你
You are not in the Calls?
Insta
Calls?
一种社交网络  在上面分享照片和视频的移动平台
Social networking, photo and video sharing, mobile platforms ...
我不喜欢跟风
It's not my style to do what everyone else does.
你可以通过网络来买票
You can buy tickets over the Internet.
这对你可能有点难  为什么
It will be difficult for you. Why
没有我你根本没法生活
you can not live without me.
只有优先通行证你才能不用排队  那样会更快
Only with a priority pass, you have no queue. It's faster.
克莱尔  你还好么  有什么问题么
Claire, how are you? Something wrong?
没有  事实上
No, or indeed.
有一个无礼的家伙
A rude guy.
说说  是谁
Tell me. Who is it?
没什么  就是一个被迷倒了的男孩
Nothing, just a boy who is enthusiastic.
一个学生  他喜欢玩火  不
A student? He likes to play with fire. Do not.
或许  你不会去玩那个美洲狮的对吧
Perhaps. You will not play with it like a puma, are you?
我没有
I do not play.
太危险了
This is serious.
我们把女人称为美洲狮  怎么变成了男人
We call Cougars women who do like men?
那是个男人  对么
He is a man, right?
男人和年轻女人们倒是常有发生  人们也不会觉得奇怪
Men with younger women are always there. You know, they think rightly so.
那可不一样  那可不是一回事
It is not the same, not really. It's a different level.
恶魔的辩护
The devil's advocate.
我想知道你到底想要什么
I want to know exactly what you want.
你让我着迷
You intrigue me.
是吗  为什么
Same?
你的态度
Their behavior ...
怎么了
How I behave?
很神秘
Intriguing.
如果我们一定要从20世纪选出一个独立的女性作家
If we want to find a writer independent in the 20th century,
我们一定会选玛格丽特·杜拉斯
It is necessary to analyze the personality of Marguerite Duras.
她写道  （玛格丽特·杜拉斯《情人》  王道乾译）
"Too fast," she wrote,
“太晚了  太晚了  在我这一生中
也过于匆匆  才十八岁  就已经是太迟了
"it was too late in my life. It was too late to 18 years.
在十八岁和二十五岁之间  我原来的容貌早已不知去向
Between 18 and 25 years my face went in an unexpected way.
我不知道是不是所有的人都这样  我从来不曾问过什么人
I never asked if everyone asked this
好像有谁对我讲过时间转瞬即逝
but I had heard about the progress of time from the moment that sometimes you get caught
在一生最年轻的岁月  最可赞叹的年华”
while in his youth, the most celebrated years."
一字一句都选得小心谨慎
Each word was chosen carefully.
但我犯了一个小错误
A small mistake on my part,
我说错了一句话  然后
a poor choice of words and
魔法就会消失
magic can go up in smoke.
你知道什么能让我高兴吗
You know what I like?
告诉我吧
Tell me!
一张你的  真正的照片
A photo Real OF YOU !!!
我不能拒绝给他照片
I could not refuse him this picture.
为什么
Why not?
那样他就会开始怀疑
Then he would suspect something.
我便不能再回头
I could not go back.
我觉得这是个谜
That excited me, I think.
就在那个时候
It was then
开始了螺旋的循环
my spiral began.
螺旋的循环
A spiral?
我给了克拉拉一张真实的面孔
I would give a real face to Clara Antunes.
喂
Hello.
我是克拉拉
It's Clara.
你有私人电话吗
You have a limited number?
我想确定
I want to make sure that you do not
你不是精神变态
It is a psychopath.
我懂了
I get it.
嗯
E...
我听起来像嗜血法医吗  不
I do not seem Dexter? Not.
你声音听起来
His voice sounds ...
很奇妙  和我想象的不一样
Strange, it is different than I had imagined.
嗯  我
Well I ...
抱歉
Excuse me.
不用道歉  你
It is not necessary. You ...
你声音很动听
You have a beautiful voice.
说实话  我觉得我的声音
Honestly, I find my own voice
非常恼人
terribly irritating.
不是这样的
No, it's not.
你真好
That's nice of you.
你的声音听起来
His voice sounds
很年轻
very young.
你几岁了  说实话
How old are you exactly?
你成年了吧
You're an adult, right?
24岁  对吗
24, no?
快25了
Almost 25.
你听起来更年轻  人家也这样说
You look younger. I often hear it.
我发了一张照片
I posted a photo.
不喜欢吗
You do not like?
我很喜欢
Yes I loved it.
你喜欢我咯
So you like it, huh?
嗯  可以这么说
Yes, you could say that.
看到我的评论了吗
Have you seen my comment?
我怎么会不喜欢这个如此美丽的女人
How not like this sublime creature?
谢谢
Thanks.
那
Good ...
我现在就想要你的电话  行吗
Can I have your phone number now?
好吧
Ok.
不仅隐藏着  现在都沉默了
Not just unlocked, but it will be great.
克拉拉
Clara...
这是谁的照片
Who was this picture?
不知道  我随便选的
I have no idea. I chose by accident.
你不觉得如果亚历克斯跟别人介绍你  看到的不是你
This does not bother you, the way Alex would imagine you, the fact that he did not see you
而是另一个女人
but another woman?
没  我真的没想过
No, not really.
他说他喜欢我的声音
He said he liked my voice.
我说的话  我的想法  那个真正的我
My words, my way of thinking, this really is me.
如果我说了实话  在Facebook上给他一张真实的照片
If I had told the truth and posted a real picture on Facebook,
他可能都不会跟我做朋友
he would not accept me as a friend.
他肯定不想遇到我这样的女人
At least he would have no desire to want to meet a woman like me.
“我这样的女人  ”
"A woman like me?"
是啊  一个女人
Yes, a woman
眼皮沉重  面容苍白
with heavy eyelids and a pale complexion.
你希望别人觉得你年轻美丽
It is important for you people think you're young, beautiful.
不是吗
Not?
我从没想过放弃那种快乐
I never wanted to give up this pleasure.
我希望人们欣赏我  喜欢我  难道你不是吗
I like to think that people will look at me and will find me beautiful. Not you?
你正是给这个男人
And yet, it is precisely for this man
发了一张另一个女人的照片
who sent a photo of another woman.
我确实这样做了
Yes, I did the opposite.
就好像
As if ...
我没给自己出现在他眼前的机会
I did not give me a chance to be in his sight.
你现在随时都可以打我电话  沉默的克拉拉
Now you can call me whenever you want, Clara, the changes.
在他的分析里  波德莱尔侯爵把梅尔泰伊看作女版的答尔丢夫（莫里哀《伪君子》）
Baudelaire analyzes the Marquise de Merteuil,
始终领先一步  比法尔曼更优秀
a female character always one step ahead and above Valmont.
他最感兴趣的不是她相比法尔曼的优越之处
But what most interested him, was not his superiority Valmont,
而是她作为一个女人的反抗  她反抗着
but his rebellion as a woman, his rebellion
反抗着这个虚伪的世界
against a hypocritical society.
翻开书  看81号信件
Open your books and go to page 81.
9个未接来电
9 missed calls
我和他在一起的时候  才能感受到生活的动感
When I was with him, I felt fly for life.
梅尔泰伊早就决定去创造一个独特的时代
Mrs.. Merteuil soon decided to create a unique self.
我从来没有如此有活力
I never felt so full of life.
我用不着假装24岁
I do not pretend to have 24 years.
我就是24岁
I was 24 years old.
你认识的男的多吗
Did you know many men?
在Facebook上
No Facebook?
不  我意思是
No, I mean,
对你有特殊意义的男人  对我有特殊意义的男人
men who meant something to you. A man really mattered to me.
克拉拉  你还不到25岁  有大把时间
You do not have 25 years. You have much time.
你还想他吗
You still think about him?
差不多
Preferably ...
我只记得美好的时刻  但是
I remember only the beautiful moments, but
挺艰难的
it's difficult.
你们谈论些什么
What did you talk about?
戏剧  艺术
Of theater, art,
文学
literature.
哦  你跟一个有学问的人在一起
Okay, so you've been with an intellectual?
是  他年纪比你大吗
Yes. He was older than you?
大一点点
A little.
跟我这种男人在一起你会无聊死的
You'll be bored to death with a man like me.
我看起来无聊吗
I pass that impression?
倒也不是
Not really.
很长时间以来
It's been a long time
这是我第一次跟别人聊得那么愉快
I did not feel so comfortable with someone.
这让我放心了
That reassures me.
克拉拉  嗯
Clear? Yes?
我感觉我们之间有什么变了
I think something is happening.
这种变化
This is not so
不是一两天
in one day.
有时候
Sometimes yes.
这么说  就对了
This is proof.
你好  最近怎么样  挺好  你的头发看起来不错
Hello how are you? Yes, it was well your new haircut.
谢谢  看起来很漂亮
Thanks. You look great.
你看起来也挺好  我看情况的
You too, by the way. I'm watching my condition.
10号11号到卡鲁尔  12号去洛桑
吉伊  我才不关心你的剧演行程
10:11 in Caluire, 12 in Lausanne 14 in Geneva ... Gilles, I shit for their tour of the theater.
我会解释的  几个星期里我会赶上的
我们不会改变日程的
I will explain. I will take them a few weeks later. We will not change the schedule.
找你的新女朋友解决去  毕竟她没什么事
Solve with his girlfriend. She's not a fucking to do.
我的“女人”  一个法语老师竟然这样说
A fuck? And a French teacher says so.
我可不想让她单独和学生们在一起  我改变主意了
She can take care of them now? I changed my mind.
变得自私真是件好事  和你一起过了20年我才意识到
So nice to be selfish. It cost me over 20 years with you to learn this.
别问我为什么
Do not ask me why.
你肯定遇上谁了
You met someone.
你想知道吗  我只想知道你最近怎么样
Would you like to know, is not it? I just want to know how you are.
如果你想知道的话  他很帅
I met someone, if you want to know. He is handsome.
很体贴
He's suit.
和他在一起
And with it all is
非常舒服  恭喜
to relax. Congratulations.
我开始从你的阴影里走出来了  感觉真的很好
I begin to free myself from you. It is very cool.
派对怎么样
How was the party?
太糟糕了  真的  怎么可能
It was terrible. Truth? Why?
大家平均55岁  难以置信
The average age was 55 years. Unbelievable.
你开玩笑吧  太可怕了
You do not mean it. What the hell!
不敢相信
I can not believe.
他们尽力装扮你
They were trying to win you.
也许吧
Perhaps.
你回家了吗  已经上床了
You're already at home? I'm already in bed.
你穿着什么呢
What are you wearing?
低领毛衣
A low-cut sweater,
内裤
panty.
没穿内衣
You're naked under your sweater?
是
Sim...
脱下衣服
Lift-a.
我的手在抚摸你的腹部  你感觉到了吗
I put my hand on her belly. Do you feel it?
是的  我感觉到了
Yes, I feel it.
我的手慢慢向上挪动
Slip slowly
到胸部
in your chest.
嗯  你的乳房如此美丽
Yes ... You have beautiful breasts.
圆润健壮
Round and robust.
我想亲吻它们  亲吻吧
I want to kiss them. Kiss them.
我亲吻你的乳头
I kiss your nipples.
你感觉得到我吮吸你的乳头吗
Do you feel that I am sucking her nipples?
你知道现在我想干什么吗
You know what I want while I suck your nipples?
我把手伸进了你的内裤
You put your hand inside her panties.
我也想要
I want too.
你也想要  是的
You want it, right? Yes.
告诉我
Say it.
我想
I want
把一只手指伸到内裤下面
a finger inside my panties, let it slide.
来吧
Then do it.
什么感觉
How do you feel?
温热  又热又潮
Warm. Hot and wet?
很热  很湿
Very hot and very humid.
你摸到阴唇了吗
You feel your pussy?
继续来吧
Go ahead, do it.
用你的手指继续
I am very excited that you are touching. Continues.
我想听你的呻吟
I want to hear you moan.
我硬了
You make me go crazy.
我进来了
I'm coming at you.
继续
Comes.
来吧
So let's go.
好舒服
Delicious...
这太
Is so ...
亚历克斯
Alex.
哦  亲爱的
Oh dear.
亲爱的
Dear...
我太想做爱了
I miss making love.
不只是
Not only the ...
但那亲吻  那爱抚
But the kisses, caresses ...
互相爱抚
touching each other
或是真正的爱抚
or actually being touched.
没有欲望  爱会变成什么呢
What is love without desire?
说说你自己  我什么都告诉你了  但你
Tell me about you. I tell you everything and you ...
你什么都没说
You do not say anything.
我只是一个暂时让你吐露心声的密友  只要不针对我
I'm just temporary confidant of a message that was not for me.
你完全是有目的的  是  我是医生
So you're not flexible? No, I'm a doctor.
你的医生
Your doctor.
不是你的朋友
Not your friend.
你从来没跟病人睡过
You've never been in bed with a client?
经常会有
This happens often,
有人渴望他的心理医生  不是吗
someone wants your therapist, right?
所以算是
We can say
治疗的一部分
that sometimes part of the process.
治疗
The process.
心理治愈的过程
The healing process.
对  这是对病人而言  那么对医生而言呢
Yes, for the patient, but what about the doctor?
我们在和病人相处的过程中得到的
We learn something of ourselves with each patient.
有时候是
Sometimes we have a benefit
一些理论  有时是
sometimes theoretical and
一些私事
personal benefit.
让你激动了吗
It made you excited?
那段在电话中和亚历克斯的场景  激动吗
This scene in the car with Alex on the phone, huh?
有明确规定的  专业委员会制定的
Claire, there are limits that have been established by medical codes of conduct.
所以我们不能见面  下星期不行
So we can not see? Not next week.
我得照顾我侄女  你答应我的
I have to take care of my niece. You promised.
我时间很紧  对不起
I really have no time. Excuse me.
我们不能这样下去  我想见你
We can not continue like this. I want to see you.
这很复杂  相信我
It's complicated. I understand now.
我很尽力了  你能不能告诉我你没在想别的
I really do my best, but unless you do not think about anything else.
她在干嘛
What is she doing?
她忘了我们了吗
Did she forgotten us?
我很爱你  亚历克斯  真的  跟你在一起我很开心
I'm madly in love with you, Alex. Same. I feel comfortable with you.
我也很想见你  让你感受到别的一切都不重要了
I also want to see you, feel you. Than all the rest does not exist.
我在开车  我待会打给你  好吗
I'm in the car now. I'll call you back. OK?
是你们的爸爸
It was his father.
快去抢
Come on.
犯规
Lack!
那是犯规
It is a lack!
这怎么判的  该买副眼睛了
That judge ... Buy a fucking spectacles.
妈妈  坐下  他看我的眼神很肮脏  但那是真的
Mom, sit down. He looked me dirty way, but it's true.
你有孩子吗  医生
You have kids, Doctor?
你肯定有一个睿智的丈夫
You must have a brilliant man.
或者没有
Or not.
从来不说说你的看法  不难受吗
It is not frustrating never be able to give your opinion?
如果你知道了我在想什么
If you know what goes through my head sometimes
你可能就坐不稳了
you fall from your chair.
我们在讨论孩子
We talked about the kids.
对  我的儿子们
Yes, my children.
我的儿子们
My children.
他们在父亲身边的时候
When they were with the father ...
我感觉很难相处  为什么很难
I found it difficult. Why so hard?
所以我就放手了
So I let myself go.
多久了
Until where?
自从
Until the time
我开始觉得自己是克拉拉  而不是克莱尔
I felt more like Clara than Claire.
你觉得我跟别的女陔一样
You imagine me like any other girl.
克拉拉
Clara ...
你不认识我
But you do not know me.
我知道你是独一无二的
I know that you are unique.
是
Sim.
我们不能太快
You should not go too fast.
即使对我们来说很艰难
Even if it is difficult for both of us.
这让我抓狂
That drives me crazy.
好  给耐心先生送个礼物
Ok, this one to Mr. Ongeduld.
你还没说那照片是哪里来的
You have not said where it comes from this photo
还有那个视频
or this video.
对  看看你的笔记  我在谷歌上随便找的
Yes, see your notes. It happened to find them on Google.
碰巧找到的  真的
By chance, really?
我怎么会撒谎
Why would I lie?
他爱上的  是照片里的年轻女人
This is the face he loves. The photo of this young.
这是
It is not
很重要的事
nothing or unimportant.
那是个陌生人
He was a stranger.
是
Sim.
这么容易就可以拿到别人的照片和视频
You can easily find the photos and videos of a stranger?
你是活在哪个世界里  这当然很简单
In what world do you live in? Of course it is easy.
每个人都在Facebook上发动态  就可以拿到照片了
Facebook and show others your life. It is there to pick up.
克莱尔  这不是审问  但是你如果不说真话  我帮不上你
Claire, is not an interrogation and if you are not telling the truth, I can not help it.
嗯  那有什么区别
Well, what difference does it make?
你会喜欢的
You will enjoy it.
那是我侄女卡迪娅的照片
It was a picture of my niece Katia.
满意了  你搞懂了吧
Satisfied? Do you get along with it, is not it?
你的侄女
Your niece?
一个金发女郎  亚历克斯好像喜欢金发的  就是这样
A beautiful blonde. Alex preferred blondes. And it all.
就这样  对  就这样
And it all? Yes, no more.
说说你的侄女
Tell me about this niece.
好  但没什么好说的
Well, but there is little to say.
卡迪娅是我兄弟的女儿
Katia is the daughter of my brother.
他和他妻子事故死后
After his death with his wife,
她就成了孤儿
she suddenly orphaned. Only that.
我没明白  我把侄女带到我家里
I do not understand what you mean. I took my niece home.
就像她是我女儿一样照顾她  虽然我以前不认识她
I took care of her like a daughter, though I knew very little before.
她知道
She knows
你用了她的照片吗
you used this photo?
她不知道  我们很久没见了
No, by the way, we do not see ourselves more.
遗产问题解决后  卡迪娅就去了挪威
After the issue of inheritance was settled, Katia went to Norway.
所以你用了她的脸  她的年龄  还有她的人生
So you have her face, her age, her story.
你想要什么
What are you looking for?
另一段人生
Another life?
不是另一段人生  是我自己的人生
No other life, my own.
终于成功了
Finally.
我昨天没出去  一直在下雨
I did not go out yesterday. It was raining.
我这也是
Also here.
我在想
I thought ...
她也许会有时间打电话给我
Maybe she has time to call me.
我要睡觉了
I have to go to bed.
你要再聊一会儿吗
You want me to stay?
我快累死了
I am falling from fatigue.
你有时候听起来就像是个母亲
Sometimes you talk like a mother.
如果我老了
You still like me if
你还会爱我吗
I stay old?
多老
How old?
50.
50  那还是有可能的
50? It's still possible.
我们还有完整的人生
We still have all our lives.
你刚在等我  当然
You waited for me? Clear.
你很甜  你在做什么  准备去旅游
Very kind. What did you do in the meantime? I prepared my trip.
什么旅行
What trip?
这个月底我要去果阿旅行
I'm going to Goa at the end of the month.
一个人
Alone?
不是  和我室友鲁多一起去  我跟你说过他
No, with my roommate. You know, Ludo. I told you about it.
要多久  两个月
How much time? Two months.
你害怕没了我你会没法活吗
Are you afraid of not being able to live without me?
克拉拉
Clara?
这事你知道多久了
How long have you known?
很长时间了
Long time.
但你现在才告诉我
And you just say that now.
你出乎意料地出现
You came unexpectedly beautiful.
跟你说  一起去吧
What do you know? Come with me.
我不行  别实习了吧
I can not. Yeah, just get out of your internship.
我们只有一次人生
We live only once.
我去了果阿对我们有什么影响呢
What will change for us while I'm in Goa?
我不敢想象你在那么远的地方
I think scary to think that you are far, so far.
我们不能互相限制  对吧
Not that we meet can improve, right?
你想我吗  你想见我吗
I miss you. Do you want to see me?
当然
Sure.
当然  你不是这样吗
Makes sense. Is that you?
是  但是
Yes but
我很害怕
I'm so afraid ...
我害怕会让你失望  当然不会
I'm afraid to disappoint you. No, of course.
这点我很清楚
I know for sure.
我也害怕让你失望
I'm also afraid to disappoint her.
克拉拉
Clara.
你在这干什么
What are you doing here?
出去走会儿吗  呼吸点新鲜空气
Come on out? I need fresh air.
好  来吧
OK, let's go.
我没法忘记他
I can not forget.
你忘不了什么
What you can not forget?
他已经成了我生活的中心
He is the center of my universe.
他去果阿旅行这段时间
我们每天聊天  甚至一天好几次
During your trip to Goa, we talk every day. Often up.
多希望可以一直这样
If only it could stay like this ...
他回来以后  开始变得越来越急切
When he returned, he began to push more and more
越来越难停下
and it became more difficult to keep the boat out.
惊喜  我今天早上回来了
A surprise? I landed this morning.
亚历克斯将在三分钟内见到克拉拉
Alex will be with Clara in three minutes.
我在这
I was there,
跟你在同一个城市
in the same town as you.
我做不到  今天不行
I could not today.
等等  这不是很好
Wait, is depressing.
你这是精神变态  你在玩弄我
You're a psychopath. You do not care about me.
你疯了  不是  我
Are you crazy. Not me ...
嘿
Hello.
你在这干什么  今天是周日
What are you doing here? It's Sunday.
当然  我在等你  我都有点担心了
Of course, I was already waiting for you. I was already a little worried.
也许吧
Leave quiet.
怎么回事  我去收拾桌子
What is it? I'll set the table.
那是谁  你在干什么
Who was? What do you do...
有朋友突然过来
Some friends arrived unexpectedly.
你讲话声音这么轻  你在开派对
我要挂了  待会打给你
You speak softly. Do you have a party? I have to turn off. I'll call you.
不  你瞎说  你在开玩笑吗  克拉拉  我受够了
No, you do not mean it. Are you kidding me? Clara, I'm sick of it.
我一直在听你的  现在都不能打电话了  你怎么了
I always adapted myself to you. We can not even call us now? What is your problem?
冰箱空了  我待会做煎饼
The refrigerator is empty. I'll make pancakes.
没有鸡蛋了
It has no eggs.
什么
Is that...
我得告诉你
I have something to tell you.
什么
Is that...
我有别人
I have a relationship.
我们住在一起
We live together.
已经很久了
How long?
在见到你之前的几个月
A few months before you. I do not know so well.
干 你就这样告诉我
Damn it. And you tell me ...
就不能早点告诉我吗  我试过了
You could not have said this before? I tried.
你跟他说过我吗
He knows me?
没有
Do not.
吉伊很嫉妒偏执  我们关系不是很好  所以
Gilles is very jealous and paranoid. Things are not going very well between us. So ...
啊  我
Well I ...
我现在知道你为什么不愿意见我了
Now I understand why you do not want to see me.
我像白痴一样等你  几个星期了  对不起  亚历克斯
You kept me online for weeks. I'm sorry, Alex.
这真的伤到我了
it hurts.
对不起
Excuse me.
我得挂了  我要消化一下
I have to turn off. I have to deal with it.
对不起
Excuse me.
嘿  克拉拉
Hello, Clara.
我不知道你怎么样  但我真的完全迷失了
I do not know how you are, but I'm completely lost
我被你迷成这样
for being so captivated by you.
我什么都做不成了  我要疯了
I can not do anything. I am getting crazy.
我下星期来巴黎  我的火车下午3:02到蒙巴纳斯
I will be in Paris on Thursday next fair. My train arrives at Montparnasse at 15:02.
不要打电话也不要发消息
Do not call me or send me messages.
如果你真的关心我  你就来见我
If you really care for me, be there.
你无法想象我有多想见你
You do not imagine how much I'd like to meet you.
我逐渐无法忍受  我必须做出决定  别无他路
It became unbearable. I needed to cut the knot, there was nothing.
我伤透了心
It broke my heart.
当我看着坐在车上的他  那么年轻  那么脆弱
But when I saw him on the bus, so young and vulnerable,
我才明白那种感觉
I knew the moment had come.
给我的伤害那么深
It hurt me a lot.
亚历克斯  昨天出了点问题
Alex, something unexpected happened yesterday.
昨天吉伊向我求婚了
Gilles asked me to marry.
我同意了
I said yes.
我们要搬去巴西了
Let us leave to live in Brazil.
他拿到了那里的工作
He accepted a job there.
我觉得我的选择是正确的
I know I'm making the right choice.
你和我之间  只是一场白日梦
You and I live in a dream with our eyes open.
很美妙
It was wonderful
但那也只是一场梦
but it was just a dream.
不要对我痴迷
Do not be mad with me.
我会一直在心里给你留下空间
I always keep a place for you in my heart.
我就如合上了小说一般恢复以往的生活
I resumed my old life as you close a novel.
痛苦的
Wound,
茫然的
crushed,
老迈的生活
old.
我想再联系他的时候已经太晚了
When I wanted to get in touch again, it was too late.
他的账号已经不存在了
The page I was gone.
亚历克斯消失了  他比我更激进
When disappearing, Alex became more radical than me and somehow
某种程度上  也更坚强
stronger too.
你好
Hello.
我一直很忙
I was busy. And it all.
就是这样
Indeed.
很有见地嘛
What wit, huh?
我没有犹豫太久  只有这样才能知道亚历克斯的下落
I did not hesitate long. It was the only way to get information about Alex.
你看起来很美  谢谢
You are magnificent. Thank you very much.
我今年基本上一直在工作
I did not stop this year between my publication and the course.
你呢  你的建筑项目怎么样
Is that you? Continues its construction projects?
平平淡淡  你看起来很累  没事吧
Quiet. You look tired. How are you doing?
没事  没事
Yes Yes.
最近过得有点艰难  艰难
It's a bit difficult now. Difficult?
你还记得我的朋友亚历克斯吗
You remember my friend Alex?
那个摄影师  有点印象
The photographer. Yes, vaguely.
他出车祸了
He was in a car accident.
他开车驶下了悬崖
He fell into a cliff.
难以置信  不是吗
Amazing, no?
就因为他在Facebook上认识了一个从没见过面的精神变态
Because of a psychopath who he met on Facebook, but never found.
警察发现他没有刹车
The police saw that he did not brake the car.
他死了
He is dead.
抱歉
Excuse me.
喂
Hello?
一个人如果死了
If someone dies,
怎么处理他的虚拟身份呢
what we do with your virtual identity?
是删掉它还是任由它去呢
We leave it as is? We exclude?
能选择什么呢
What kind of choice do we have?
等等
Wait.
我把它写下来了
I wrote.
这很重要
It was vital, necessary.
我想听听你的看法  这很重要
I want to hear your opinion. Is important.
我会去读的
I will read.
真正的秘密  克莱尔·米约
Secrets Royal by Claire Millaud
很长时间我们都没什么结果  让人难以忍受
For a long time, the idea that nothing happened between us was unbearable.
放下它就好像放弃了生命
Stop was like giving up on life.
最后我还是痴迷于这个男人
In the end I was crazy for this man.
我为什么要放弃  去试试又能有什么损失
Why give up? How much would it cost me to try?
害怕无法取代克拉拉
The fear of Clara is unable to replace?
亚历克斯会不高兴
Alex, he would be unhappy?
但我可以去安慰他
But I could comfort him.
不好意思  我觉得我认识你
Sorry, I think I know you.
抱歉  我觉得我认识你
Excuse me. I think I know you.
你不是鲁多的朋友嘛  鲁多维克  是的
You're no friend of Ludo? Ludovic? Yes...
对的  我认识他  我是他前妻  现在是朋友
I know, I'm your ... A friend from the past.
没想起来吗
No memory?
牡蛎  在打电话的时候  哦对对
That the oysters on the phone. Ah yes.
你还是跟他住在索姆河吗
Are you still living with him in the Somme?
他还没有赶走我
He has not kicked me out.
那你脾气肯定挺好
So you must have a good character.
你是个摄影师
You are photographer?
差不多吧
More or less.
我在一个展览上工作
I'm working on an exhibition.
鲁多跟我说过
Ludo had told me about it.
他给我看过你拍的照片
He had shown his photos.
我觉得挺漂亮的
I found them very beautiful.
谢谢
Thanks.
我下一站下车
I have to get off at the next.
你拍肖像照吗  我不是指那些街上的一般照片
You also do portraits? I mean, not exposed photos in the street,
是用来
more portraits ...
是的  我拍的  我拍肖像还有相册
Yes, me too. I do portraits, photo albums.
除了婚礼我什么都拍
I do everything except marriages.
我想给我下一本书的出版准备一些照片
I need a photo for my next book.
一般他们都会派摄影师的  但
They usually send a photographer, but now ...
我想到了你  或许你可以帮我
It's funny I know you. Maybe you can ...
行  可以
Yes, certainly.
我一直在找些东西拍  那很好
I'm looking for a job. Then that would be great.
很好  能问下你电话多少吗  如果你感兴趣的话
That's crazy. Can I have your phone number? If you are interested ...
抱歉  我忘记你的名字了  克莱尔
Sorry, I forgot your name. Claire.
我叫克莱尔
My name is Claire.
但在易卜生的《玩偶之家》里主要讲的是诺拉
But it's mostly about Nora at Ibsen mode. A dollhouse.
那个玩偶  善良的妻子
The doll, the good woman,
负责的母亲  就是她
responsible mother. She is like this.
这个戏剧讲的就是她意识的觉醒
The play speaks of the awakening of his conscience.
在社会压迫下一个女人对其身份的解放
The emancipation of a woman outside a pre-defined role for society.
现在  一个多世纪以后  拒绝约束依旧是我们的心声
And today, over a century later, we can say that this question us still
你还是不想依循于禁锢你的框架
we must refuse to conform and submit to the rules within which we are locked.
他怎么做到的
How did he do it?
什么  谁
What? Who?
鲁多  他怎么迷倒你的  你很美  很上镜
Ludo. As he did to be with such a beautiful woman? You're super photogenic.
很好  可不可以
Very good. Come on , maybe,
解一下领口的扣子  衬衣
loosen the top button? From my blouse?
这书是写给学者看的  不知道
The book is for college. I do not know if ...
那更可以去吸引读者了
One more reason to entice the reader.
很好
Good...
非常好
Super.
坐下来点  这样放轻松点
And .... You can relax a little more?
抱歉  我动了  没事
Sorry, I got out of position. I do not care.
你结婚了吗  有孩子吗  离婚了  是的  都是的
Are you married, children, divorced? Indeed.
全部三个  还是按着顺序
I hit all three. And in the right order.
30年里都走了一遍  你有什么瞒着我
And all around his 30 years. You are hiding something from me.
我可以
I can
试试这样吗
try something?
你累吗要休息吗  没事  继续
Do you agree or want to take a break? No, continue.
我全都告诉你
I have nothing to hide.
我跟一个对我来讲非常重要的男人结婚了20年
I was married for 20 years to a man who was everything to me.
在那之前我认识挺多小伙  但太久了都忘记了
Before him I was with two guys, but that was long ago. I forgot about them.
我有两个孩子  两个男孩
I had two children. Two boys.
要是可以给我的孩子喂奶  我可以是个好母亲
I thought it would be a good mother if I gave them the breast.
我的乳房一直没康复  胃也不好
My breasts never recovered, nor my stomach.
我丈夫找了一个年轻女人  年轻得可以做我女儿
My husband left me for a woman who could be my daughter.
那时候我觉得我活不下去了
When it happened, I thought I would die of grief.
我太激动了  不知道怎么描述
I am very passionate about. This is the right word.
但我也可以很快乐
But I can also be happy.
我觉得
So I think
你知道的够多了
you know almost everything.
太疯狂了
It's crazy.
什么
O homeland?
没什么  我们的相遇  都太疯狂了
Anything. Our meeting. That's crazy.
你看看  把这张做成肖像  有点锐利
So, here is where you cut into the picture. It's a little cleaner.
这张不错
I like it.
这张很美  还有一张笑着的  我最喜欢
This is beautiful and we also have one with a smile and I like it.
喜欢吗  是
You too? Yes.
日日夜夜的爱
We made love day and night.
我们要弥补逝去的时间
We had to catch up.
很快我们同居了  是他搬了过来
We started living together very fast, or actually he moved in with me.
熄灭掉我的眼睛  我仍能看见你（里尔克《熄灭我的眼睛》）
"Close my eyes I still be able to see you
猛关上我的耳朵  我仍能听见你
Close my ears I still be able to hear you
没有脚足  我仍能走向你
And no feet, I can still follow you
没有嘴巴  我仍能呼唤你
And even without mouth I can still call you "
读下去  不  你来
Read the following. Not you.
来吧  读下去
Please. Come on.
折断我双臂  我就用我的心  紧抓住你  就像用手
"Break my arms and I embrace you with my heart, as if with one hand
停住我的心  我的脑就跳动
Hold my heart and my brain will hit, igniting my brain
你再把火焰掷进我脑里  我就在我血液上携载你
My blood will take you "
我爱你
I love you.
我太爱你了  我也爱你
I love you so much. I love you too.
你知道我最爱你什么吗
You know what I like?
有点奇怪
Crazy
是你的声音
but it is his voice.
克莱尔的声音就是克拉拉的声音
Claire's voice is clear.
他肯定还在想她
Of course, he always thought of her.
我可以取代她的脸庞吗
I thought so naively that my face would replace it?
我怎么会忘记克拉拉走后  对他  我只是个安慰
How could I forget that I was a consolation because he had lost?
更可怕的是  他是通过我爱上了她
Even worse. He loved her through me.
没有比不存在的竞争对手更可怕了
There is no rival greater than that which does not exist.
亚历克斯  我忘不了你  我跟吉伊分开了
Alex, I could not forget you. Gilles ended.
我回巴黎了  我爱你  我很想你
I'm back in Paris. I love you, I missed you.
我不知道你在哪  如果你还爱我  来法兰西咖啡见我
I do not know where you are, but if you still have love for me, to come to the French cafe.
晚上六点到八点我都在那  别打我电话  如果你没来
I'll be there between 18h and 20h. Try not to call. If you do not come,
我就不再联系你了  我保证  克拉拉
you'll never hear from me. I promise. Your Clara.
你好了吗  好了
You're ready? Yes.
我们走  好
Here we go. Yes.
你真的不想呆家里  不了  我想到外面吃午饭
You really do not want to stay home? No, I want to have lunch somewhere.
我想吃的是你
The fact is, I'd rather eat you.
我们去看电影吗
Let's go to the movies?
好啊
No doubt.
看看有什么电影
See what happens.
我去穿件毛衣
I'll get a sweater.
有点冷
I am cold.
欢迎回来  克拉拉
Welcome, Clara.
可以听到尖叫声  刹车声还有撞击声  最后一片沉静
We heard shouting, screaming brakes, a coup. And finally silence.
在电影里  结局可能就是这样
In a film could end like this.
是啊  那现实世界呢
Yes, and in fact?
为什么是这样的结果
Why do not you find a happy ending?
即使是在虚幻的世界里  你也很不幸  你好像想伤害自己
Even in a fantasy world, you do not allow yourself to be lucky, as if to hurt
一次又一次
repeatedly.
谁伤害了你  克莱尔
Who hurt you, Claire?
谁伤害了你
Who hurt you?
你知道我从卡迪娅那里偷来了什么吗
You know what I stole from Katia?
很久我才明白  我侄女卡迪娅的态度
It took me long to realize but the attitude of Katia, my niece,
很长一段时间里
became hostile with me
对我很有敌意
over time.
在我结过婚后  吉伊是他叔叔
Gilles is his uncle, only through our marriage.
我一直听他说  没有亲属关系
I was told often enough, no blood relationship.
“她爱我  我爱她  没有恶劣的情节  仅仅是爱”
"She loves me, I love her , no aggravating circumstance, only love."
这是他说的
His words.
实际上
Indeed ...
27岁的年龄差比上20年的婚姻
The age difference of 27 years for 20 years of marriage.
卡迪娅没有回到挪威  她和她丈夫一起住
Katia did not return to Norway. She moved in with my husband.
我没法告诉你
I could not tell you.
在书里也不行
Even write.
他们害死了我  她害死了我
They destroyed me. She destroyed me.
是她  你的竞争对手
But she was his rival
你想假扮她
you chose to incarnate?
对
Sim.
我想夺走她的美貌  她的年轻
I wanted her beauty, her childhood.
我嫉妒她的幸福  她偷走了我的
I envied her for her happiness, she stole mine.
我很嫉妒
I was jealous.
实际上你一直在逃避现实  不想去接受
Everything happens as if you recussasse the truth, as you escape the truth.
渴望永恒  幻想永远年轻
The desire for eternity, the illusion of eternal youth, yes.
我们都在逃避
We all want to get away from us,
我们总会死去的现实
from the perspective of our death.
死去我无所谓
I do not mind dying
但我被抛弃了
But yes, to be abandoned.
我们随时都可以变年轻
There is no age to be small.
我渴望有人照顾  安抚  即使是幻觉
I wanted to be dreaming, calm, even with illusions.
有多久了
After how long?
她9个月前来的
It happened about nine months.
这事影响太大了
It was far enough.
亚历克斯完全被她迷住了
Alex was completely captivated by it.
以至于他有一天给我看了条消息
So bad that it took me one day and showed a message.
我马上就听出了她的声音
I immediately recognized his voice.
一开始我不敢相信
At first I could not believe it.
我觉得只是开玩笑
I thought it was a game.
任性的游戏罢了
Perverse.
我没跟亚历克斯说什么  但我告诉他
I did not say anything to Alex, but I tried to show for it
那个叫克拉拉的女孩
this girl, that Clara,
她太完美了
it was too perfect.
最后他开始怀疑
Then he began to doubt.
克拉拉消失的时候  他删掉了他的账户
When Clara was gone, he deleted his profile.
几个月后  她给我打电话
A few months later, she called me.
我告诉她  因为她亚历克斯死了
I said he was killed because of it.
他自杀了
He had committed suicide.
我朋友快疯了  而我
My friend and I went crazy ...
我不喜欢被欺骗
I do not like to be fooled.
所以我撒了谎
So I lied.
我没明白
I dont understand...
他没死
He's not dead?
没有
Do not.
他甚至刚当上父亲
He even became a father.
他住在法国南部
He lives in southern France.
他结婚了
He's married.
上个月他当爸爸了
He became a father last month.
生了一个女儿
From a girl.
我们一开始觉得我们作了孽  但其实又没有
Sometimes we think we are guilty, but no.
我是来说再见的
I come to say goodbye.
有时候  病人得到了某些东西  又会失去
Sometimes a patient has something in it that we had and we lost.
我照你的建议去做了
I took his advice seriously.
我在写我的另一部小说
I'm still working on my manuscript.
意识到一切变得可能真的很美妙
It was good to realize that everything is possible again.
凡事都不止一种结局
That there is only one end.
是的
Do not.
对
再见  克莱尔
See you soon, Claire.
再见  医生
Bye.